In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to pronounce the SH and ZH consonant sounds.
我们将学习如何发 SH 和 ZH 辅音音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被放在一起是因为它们的口型相同。
SH is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth,
SH 是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔，
and ZH is voiced,
而 ZH 是有声的，
meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
意味着你用声带发出声音。
ZH To make these sounds,
ZH 要发出这些音，
the teeth come together,
牙齿合拢，
the corners of the lips come in,
嘴角收拢，
and the lips flare.
嘴唇张开。
The tongue lifts, so the front, middle part of the tongue is very close to the roof of the mouth,
舌头抬起，所以舌头的前中部非常接近上颚，
but not touching it.
但不接触它。
The tongue tip points forward,
舌尖向前指，
but doesn't touch anything.
但不接触任何东西。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些音。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合拢。
In the word SHOP,
在单词 SHOP 中，
the SH is at the beginning of the word.
SH 在单词的开头。
In the word WISH,
在单词 WISH 中，
it's at the end.
它在结尾。
In the word ASIA,
在单词 ASIA 中，
the ZH sound is in the middle.
ZH 音在中间。
The mouth position is always the same.
口型始终相同。
Teeth together, lips flare.
牙齿合拢，嘴唇张开。
The SH and ZH consonants.
SH 和 ZH 辅音。
SHOP, WISH,
ASIA.
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Should.
SH,
should.
Special.
SH, special.
Wash.
SH,
wash.
Measure.
ZH.
Garage.
Usual.
ZH.